Hello?
喂？
Is that… Ogawa?
是小川老師嗎？
Hello,
你好
Kiyoshi's mother!
清同學的媽媽！
Can you hear me?
聽得見嗎？
Yes. I can hear you.
是，我聽得見
This is so frustrating.
看著就煩躁
Sorry about this.
不好意思
There's no Wi-Fi here, you see.
我這裡沒有無線網路訊號
But I tried calling using my Pocket WiFi while standing on a stepladder,
不過我試著 拿著便攜式無線網路踩到梯子上
and now I can hear you.
就能聽到你們的聲音
Oh, it's her!
啊，是她！
It's her!
我認得她！
Look.
你看
She's Sakae Sakisaka, a feminist.
她叫向坂紗加惠，是女性主義者
So she was from over here.
原來她是未來的人啊
You're famous. Cool.
原來你是名人啊 跟男人比毫不遜色呢
Whatever.
好啦…
Mrs. Sakisaka, where are you right now?
向坂小姐，你目前身在何處？
Now?
目前？
I'm in front of a cafe called Scandal.
我在一間叫“緋聞”的咖啡廳前
What?
什麼？
Try entering the cafe.
你試著直接走進店裡
I'm in.
我進去了
See?
看吧
She's in the Showa era.
她在昭和時期
That means you really are in the Reiwa era.
所以說你果然在令和？
Hello.
歡迎光臨
Are you by yourself?
一位嗎？
Take any seat you like.
店裡有空桌，請隨意坐
Huh? Barkeep?
什麼？這是老闆？
-That's the barkeep?! -That's him 38 years ago.
-他是老闆？ -是38年前的他
Anyway, it's great my call went through.
不過真是萬幸，還好電話打通了
It's not great at all!
哪裡萬幸了！
Sorry for the trouble, but could you go to my house now?
太太，不好意思 能不能馬上去我家一趟？
I'll share my address.
我告訴你地址
What? Why?
什麼？為什麼啊？
My daughter is going to have rumpy-pumpy with your son!
因為我女兒會和令郎做那檔子事啦！
Rumpy-pumpy?
做那檔子事？
For some reason, the video of my daughter when she was little is here,
在我女兒小時候拍的錄影帶 不知為何在我手上
which means the porn video I confiscated from a student is inside the VCR.
這就代表我從學生那裡沒收的 色情錄影帶就在放映機中
It's of a lady teacher.
那部是女老師題材
If they watch it, your horny ape of a son will become even more like an ape!
看了那種東西你們家 血氣方剛的猴子男會更亢奮！
Kiyoshi.
阿清
Kiyoshi!
阿清！
Who are you?
你是誰啊？
Step aside!
給我讓開！
Kiyoshi!
阿清！
Are you his mother?
-難道你是他媽媽？ -阿清！
Kiyo…
阿清…
It seems he lost confidence after watching this.
他看了這個後，好像徹底喪失了自信
All I wanted to see were boobs.
我明明只想看女生的胸部
Watching something like that would make me go insane.
看到那種內容會變成蠢蛋的
I'm going to go insane.
我會變成笨蛋啦！
Where's my stupid geezer? Why isn't he coming home?
我家的臭老頭呢？他怎麼不回來？
After my baseball club activities, I boarded a bus.
我在棒球社的練習結束後搭上公車
Then a high school girl wearing a very short skirt boarded the bus.
然後有個穿超短裙子的女高中生上車
-Are these what you saw? -Yeah.
-你看到的是這個嗎？ -對
They're earphones that transmit sound via Bluetooth.
這種耳機能透過藍牙技術傳輸聲音
Transmit sound? Via Bluetooth?
藍牙？傳輸聲音？
And what happened when you stepped off the bus?
你下了公車之後發生了什麼事？
A package of hi-lite was 520 yen.
我發現一包hi-lite要520圓
I met you.
接著遇到你
I went to the toilet and saw Kyon Kyon's 40th anniversary poster.
進到廁所發現 Kyon Kyon出道40週年了
There was a hole in the wall that led to the Showa era.
牆上開了個洞 洞的另一頭就是昭和時期
You arrived here from the past by bus,
所以你搭公車，從過去來到未來
and you returned to the past through the toilet?
之後通過廁所回到過去？
So the toilet is a gateway to the Showa era.
那廁所是通往昭和的入口
Until the other day. But not anymore.
直到之前是那樣沒錯，但現在消失了
I can't go back.
我回不去
Because you renovated it!
都怪你重新裝修！
I mean, it's outdated to have a Japanese-style toilet.
蹲式廁所如今已經過時了嘛
I'm sorry, I guess.
總覺得有點對不起你
I'm the one to blame?
不過這是我的錯嗎？
Why did you come back?
那你怎麼又回來了？
Huh? Well…
什麼？這個嘛…
Because…
其實是因為…
Did you forget something here?
你有東西放在這忘了帶？
Because, um…
是因為，那個…
I was curious about you.
我放心不下你
Me?
我嗎？
Yeah, you.
沒錯，就是你
You were crying the other day.
你前幾天不是哭了嗎？
My baby finally fell asleep.
這孩子不久前終於睡著了
If you'd like, I can lend you a listening ear.
如果不嫌棄，我願意聽你訴苦喔
Sorry. I accidentally paired the earphones.
抱歉，手機自動配對了
Paired?
配對？
Your daughter… having rumpy-pumpy.
令嬡…試圖做那檔子事…
What?
什麼？
I managed to prevent them.
不過我成功攔住他們了
Also, it seems I can connect to the Wi-Fi when in this position.
另外，用這個姿勢 似乎就能接收到無線網路訊號
The stepladder had nothing to do with it.
其實跟梯子沒關係
So, what will you do?
現在怎麼辦？
Do you know how you can come back?
你知道怎麼回到這裡嗎？
I don't.
不知道
Do you?
那你知道嗎？
What's with that bus anyway?
話說那台公車到底是怎麼回事？
This is a real pain. There's a baseball match tomorrow!
我很頭大 明天可是棒球社的比賽耶！
What are you doing?!
你們在搞什麼？
What's wrong with high school girls in the Showa era?
昭和的高中女生都怎麼了？
As soon as you look away, they start going at it.
一不留神就馬上找機會上床
I can't let my guard down at all.
完全不能掉以輕心
-Shut up, you hysteric biddy! -What?
-囉嗦，你這個歇斯底里的老太婆 -你說什麼？
Who cares? It's not like it's the end of the world.
沒差吧，又沒什麼損失
Everyone else has gone through it!
其他人早就有經驗了！
Being a virgin isn't cool these days!
這個時代不流行處女了啦！
I want to live it up in my teens and become a Clarion Girl!
我要趁十幾歲的花樣年華遊戲人間 當上歌樂女郎！
This is my business card from my previous job.
這是我的名片 雖然我已經不在這間公司了
EBS? You worked at a TV station?
“EBS”？你待過電視台？
I had a passion for comedy and hoped to work with variety shows,
我熱愛搞笑 希望能參與製作綜藝節目
but I ended up in the news department.
但被分配到新聞部
I was sent to the New York branch,
我受派至紐約分部
Ryusuke Taniguchi.
名叫谷口龍介
-He's a freelance journalist now. -Wow.
-他現在是自由記者 -天哪
He's got 1.58 million subscribers!
他的訂閱人數高達158萬耶！
-What are you talking about? -Look.
-什麼東西？ -你看
Welcome to Ryusuke Taniguchi's channel, Sound Arguments.
歡迎各位來到谷口龍介的正論頻道
Today, I will present sound arguments about environmental issues.
我今天要就環境問題提出正論觀點
Waste sorting.
垃圾分類
Super important.
這行為非常重要
This is because…
至於原因呢…
Like that, he basically only presents sound arguments.
大概是這樣 他基本上就是滿嘴大道理
But the night view of New York was gorgeous,
不過紐約的夜景實在太過美麗
and it just felt like he was saying something cool.
當時覺得他的話說進了我的心坎裡
And I wanted to show myself in a wedding dress to my father soon.
而且當時也想盡快讓父親看到我出嫁
My mother passed away in the year of the Great Hanshin earthquake.
我媽在阪神大地震那年過世了
The Great Hanshin earthquake?
阪神大地震？
When you don't know something, you just Google it, like this.
遇到不懂的問題時 只需要像這樣Google一下
See?
你看
What? Are you kidding me?
不會吧？這是怎麼回事？
1995? That's nine years from now.
1995年？不就是九年後嗎？
An earthquake that big?
日本會有這麼大的地震？
Another one hit Tohoku in 2011.
2011年還發生了東北大地震
Huh, I see. I'll keep that in mind.
這樣啊，知道了 謝謝你告訴我，我會牢記在心
And then?
然後呢？
All your memories are in there, huh?
你的回憶都在那東西裡，是嗎？
Huh? Oh, yeah.
什麼？是沒錯
Losing it would be a big deal, then.
那弄丟可就糟了，然後呢？
My husband supported my decision to continue working.
我先生支持我繼續工作
And I was chosen as the assistant producer
我加入了心心念念的綜藝組
in the variety department I've been longing to join.
還被提拔為助理製作人
Just as my job was becoming interesting,
正當我覺得工作變得有點意思 不久後就發現自己懷了正人
My husband was involved in childcare and told me not to shoulder everything.
我先生也有意幫我照顧孩子
He kept telling me, "If there's anything I can do, just let me know."
“有什麼我能幫的就儘管說” 他總是這麼說
Revolting.
令人倒胃口
-What? -No, go on.
-什麼？ -沒事，你繼續
I was eager to return to work quickly.
我想早日回歸工作崗位
Even while on maternity leave, I made a project plan
產假期間還寫了企劃書
and prepared myself to rejoin the workforce.
為重返職場做準備
But I didn't pass the screening to enroll the baby in a nursery.
可是孩子沒通過托兒所的入所審核
Even though you both worked?
即使是雙薪家庭也沒通過？
The person at the ward office said,
區公所的人提出質疑
"Your husband is on paternity leave, isn't he?"
問我說“你先生請了產假，對吧？”
I'm going to share a sound argument.
在此提出正論觀點
Paternity leave.
產假
You should definitely take it.
絕對得請
I will also take time off work.
我也會休產假
The reason is…
至於原因呢…
His argument is sound, but the timing is…
這確實是正確的言論 但提出的時間點不大合適
When I spoke with my supervisor,
我找上級商量後
the company was promoting the Work Style Reform.
對方表示公司正針對 工作方式實施改革
They were planning to set up a daycare in their annex next year,
說下一年會在分棟設立托兒室
so he urged me to make use of it and share its benefits with others.
要我利用這項服務 並宣揚托兒室的優點
I finally managed to return to the office.
接著終於到了復職的那一天
Good morning!
早安！
-Good morning. -You're early.
-早啊 -你來得真早
-Sorry. -I will open the door right now.
-不好意思 -我馬上開門
Here we go.
來
-Here are his diapers and baby wipes. -Right.
-這一包是尿布和擦屁股的濕紙巾 -好
-And this is his baby food.
-這一包是離乳食品
If he refuses to eat, there's jelly in this bag.
-他不吃的話這一包裡有果凍 -好的
-Here we go, Machato. -Right.
-來，正人 -交給我吧
Be a good boy, okay?
你要乖乖的喔
-See you later. -Take care.
-麻煩你了 -你去吧
Mr. Uryu, here's the project plan I made during my maternity leave.
瓜生先生 這是我在產假期間寫的企劃書
Meet Ai, the new assistant producer.
你來認識一下小愛吧 她是新來的助理製作人
Please hand over your tasks.
就麻煩你交接了
H-Hand over?
交接？
You're being promoted to producer, and I'm stepping into an executive role.
你要從助理製作人晉升製作人 而我也要轉管理階層了
Right, of course.
是啊，說得對
Let me know if there's anything I can support you.
有我能幫的我都會做 可以儘管提出來喔
You look at the cast lineup for the day and allocate dressing rooms accordingly.
你負責查看當天的出演人員陣容
Put this person in Room D, close to the smoking area.
-給這個人吸菸區附近的D間 -好的
This duo hates each other, so assign them Rooms A and G, situated farthest apart.
這一對搭檔特別不合
Mr. Mushanokoji, the main emcee, is into feng shui and fortune-telling.
至於擔任主持人的武者小路先生 他崇尚風水和算命
So, I always switch the color of the curtains to purple.
記得每次都要 將休息室的窗簾改成紫色
Got it.
明白了
Wait. Aren't you going to take notes?
等等，你不做筆記嗎？
No, I don't use paper.
我用不慣紙張
I see.
是喔
Where are you going?
你有什麼事嗎？
To say hello to Mr. Mushanokoji.
我想跟武者小路先生問個好
No!
不行！
Never until the show is over.
正式錄影前不能打擾他
But Mr. Sakakibara will lecture you if you don't greet him,
榊原先生則相反 不去問好反而會被唸一頓
so go do it now!
-馬上去，現在就去！ -好的！
BABYSITTER
（保姆）
Your mommy is coming, okay?
媽媽快到了，再等一下好嗎？
What's the matter?
出了什麼問題嗎？
I'm so sorry.
對不起
I glanced away for a moment, and I think he may have swallowed a marble.
我一時沒看好孩子 他好像就吞下了玻璃扁珠
You think?
你不確定？
When I counted them, one was missing.
我數過後，發現少了一顆
Machato, did you swallow a marble?
正人，你吞了玻璃扁珠嗎？
Machato?
正人？
-Hello?
-喂？ -你好
I tasked Ai with booking plane tickets for the overseas location shoot.
兩週後要飛海外拍外景 我請小愛幫忙訂機票
Could you check on her?
你可以幫我確認嗎？
Economy seats will do for them.
這一區的訂經濟艙就好
These young people here should be fine with economy seats.
這一區都是年輕人，坐經濟艙就夠了 幫這些人訂經濟艙吧
But Mr. Ikusaburo Yamazaki is flying business class.
可是山崎育三郎先生坐商務艙
Won't the others with longer careers see it as unfair?
其他人不會覺得 以資歷來說自己更該坐商務艙嗎？
Then, arrange separate flights for them.
這種時候就得錯開航班
I see.
哦，原來如此
-May I? -Sure.
-借我用一下 -好
They won't know unless they are on the same flight.
見不到彼此 就不會知道對方坐什麼艙
"If I'm flying economy, they must be flying economy, too."
“既然自己是坐經濟艙 那對方也是坐經濟艙
"If I'm flying business, they must be flying economy."
自己坐商務艙 那對方還是坐經濟艙”
That's how celebrities tend to think.
那就是演藝人員的心態
That's good to know.
我學到了一課
And having a standard makes it easier.
還有一點，設下標準會比較好做事
In my case, I use Norito Yashima as the benchmark.
以我來說，我的標竿就是八嶋智人
-Mr. Yashima? The one with glasses? -Yeah, him.
-八嶋先生是戴眼鏡那位？ -對，就是他
Doesn't he seem like the type who won't complain about an economy seat?
那個人看上去 坐經濟艙也不會有怨言，對吧？
But he would appreciate a business class seat.
但讓他坐商務艙感覺就會欣喜若狂
True.
是沒錯
When in doubt, I consider whether they're above or below Yashima.
所以拿不定主意時 我會以對方在八嶋之上或之下做評估
-Your phone is ringing. -Right.
-你手機響了 -真的耶，不好意思
-Good luck.
-有勞了
-Can I look at the script? -Sure.
-腳本給我瞧瞧 -好的
-Here you go. -Thanks.
-請過目 -謝謝
Place the bento boxes in the dressing rooms,
把午餐的便當放進休息室後
then copy the second script and allocate the rooms.
再影印下一集的腳本 分發至各休息室
Um, I'm clocking out for the day.
不好意思，我今天的班就到這
What? But we're shooting two programs today.
什麼？今天要拍兩集耶
-Sorry, but my shift is over. -What are you doing, Ai?
抱歉，我們是輪班制
Your shift is over.
換班了…
-Head home already! -Right. Sorry.
-你趕緊回家 -是，抱歉
This is Elza. She's taking over for the afternoon shift.
她是上午班的艾莎
Please hand over your tasks.
就麻煩你交接了
Nagisa, are you okay?
小渚，你還好嗎？
Well, I wasn't aware they worked on a shift basis.
那個，我不知道是輪班制耶
Don't shoulder everything by yourself. If I can do anything…
凡事不要一個人自己扛
You said, "if I can do anything,"
那混帳說“有能幫上忙的儘管提” 但我又不是他
I'm not you, so I have no idea.
哪知道他能幫上哪些忙
And considering how you can help in this situation is an additional burden.
考量那傢伙在當下的情境 能幫上什麼忙又是一項新工作
In the first place, anything you can do, I can pretty much do too.
再說你能做的事，我也幾乎都能做
And there aren't too many tasks that you can handle, but I can't.
你做得到而我做不到的事情 實際上並不多
There's also the issue of whether it's something you want to do.
這又衍生出了 那傢伙到底想不想幫忙的問題
What if I request something you can do, but you react negatively?
一想到自己拜託對方 做他力所能及的事卻被他擺臭臉
It would make me feel so empty inside.
那種空虛感實在讓人受不了
It's easier to shoulder things on your own.
有些事自己扛還比較輕鬆
Exactly.
正是如此
Yikes. I can only laugh at this point.
完了，現在我也只能笑了
I don't really get it, but I made fried udon noodles.
雖然我不是很明白，但炒了盤烏龍麵
Why?
為什麼啊？
You'll try my cooking?
你願意吃啊？
Sorry.
不好意思
It would've been better if I could express what I wanted to say at the office.
真希望我在公司也能像這樣 表達出自己的心聲
The fried udon noodles are delicious.
炒烏龍麵很美味
This is a serious problem.
這問題還挺嚴重的
You're suffering all the negative effects of the Work Style Reform.
公司改革工作模式的負面影響 全壓在你一個人身上了
That day, I ended up handling the workload of filming two programs on my own,
結果那一天啊 直到最後都是我教兩個新人
while also guiding two newcomers
一次拍兩集的工作內容 並獨自扛起一切
and making five trips between the daycare room and the studio.
這期間還在托兒室及攝影棚間 來回跑了五趟
And as I was cleaning the dressing rooms…
等我收拾完休息室…
Nagisa, my shift is over. I'll see you tomorrow.
前輩，我的班就到這
I was like, "I can't take this anymore!"
當時心裡就想說“誰承受得住啊！”
And I rushed into the office's counseling room.
於是衝進公司裡的諮商室
You have a tendency to shoulder everything by yourself.
你總會想一肩扛起所有事情，對吧？
Um, were you listening?
那個，你剛剛有在認真聽嗎？
It's easier to do things by myself.
我自己做事比較沒負擔
This is just your first day back at work.
這是你復職的第一天
At this rate, you'll be exhausted, and you won't be able to enjoy your job.
這樣下去，你的身體會撐不住 工作時也無法樂在其中
About that…
關於那一點…
Is it mandatory to enjoy my job?
我非得享受不可嗎？
I spent the entire day
逼自己享受工作樂趣的壓力
struggling with the stress of feeling compelled to enjoy myself.
讓我一整天都過得筋疲力盡
What led you to join this company?
你進這間公司是想做什麼？
To create project plans for variety shows.
我想做綜藝節目的企劃
My dream is to produce a unique program with my favorite comedian.
我的夢想是和喜歡的諧星 攜手製作獨樹一格的綜藝節目
In that case, it would be a shame to let something like this bring you down.
既然如此
Don't throw away the career you've worked so hard to build.
這麼做會導致你 好不容易積累的職涯化為泡影
I see.
我明白了
Right. Absolutely.
是啊，沒錯…
Well then, I'm looking forward to continuing our collaboration. Bye.
那往後也請你多多關照，再見
What?
幹嘛？
This is a project plan for a new show that I made while on maternity leave.
這是我在產假期間 為新節目寫好的企劃書
You can show me that later. Go home already!
那不重要，趕快回家去！
They'll reprimand me for making you work unpaid overtime!
讓下屬無償加班我會被罵的！
I see.
明白了
And paper is so outdated. Email me the data.
而且現代哪有人會用紙啊
I don't "see" it at all!
我根本就不明白！
At this rate, I don't even know why I returned to the office!
再這樣下去 我都搞不懂自己為何要重返職場
Anyway, I thought I should find a proper childcare service.
我想說得先找到 合適的托兒所照顧孩子
I visited the Child Care Support Service at the ward office.
便找上區公所的育兒支援課
The Kawasumi Nursery has a waiting list of 30 people.
川澄托兒所還有30人在等候名單上
What?
怎麼會？
When I came here a year ago,
我一年前來這裡諮詢
I was told there were ten people on the waiting list and…
你們告訴我有10人在排隊…
He's been working remotely since five.
你先生五點要開始遠程辦公
I see.
我知道了
I'm Nunokawa, Mr. Taniguchi's attorney and public relations representative.
我叫布川，是谷口先生的代理律師 兼外務負責人
Until when is he working remotely?
他遠程辦公到幾點結束？
I'm unable to answer that.
恕我無法回答
It's confidential information.
這攸關公司機密
Shall I take a message? Or would you prefer a callback?
需要我幫忙傳話嗎？
Thank you for your time.
就這樣，再見
That was me.
那個人是我
At that moment,
就在那一刻
my patience reached its breaking point.
我心裡繃緊的那根弦啪地一聲就斷了
I worked hard all day
為了這一杯
for this one glass.
我今天努力了一整天
And yet…
可是…
Huh?!
搞什麼？
In the heat of the moment, I sent in my resignation to my company,
後來我就順勢向公司遞辭呈
and divorce papers to my husband.
還把離婚協議書寄給了丈夫
Why did you do that, Mr. Ogawa?
小川先生，看你做的好事
My bad. I didn't think a glass of beer would lead to a divorce.
抱歉，我沒想到 她會因為一杯啤酒而離婚
I've gotten over it already.
我已經看開了
Right now, I work as a hostess during the evenings at this bar.
如今我只有夜間時段是受雇的女店長
Because of Mr. Ogawa, or thanks to him, my life has done a complete 180.
這都要怪小川先生，應該說託他的福
Anyway, it's the last call.
總而言之
What will you do?
你要怎麼辦？
Even if trains are running, I guess you can't go home.
雖說有電車，但你也回不了家
Where do you live, Nagisa?
小渚，你家在哪？
Huh? You're coming over?
什麼？你要來我家？
Don't worry. I won't do anything.
放心，我什麼都不幹
I'll call the police if you do.
你敢做我就報警
You can stay at mine.
要不要來我家？
Where? Nearby?
在哪啊？近不近？
It's a ten-minute walk.
步行十分鐘喔，來不來？
I don't need bedding. A sofa or a sleeping bag will do.
我不需要棉被什麼的 只要有沙發或睡袋就行了
But my place is small, and I have a baby.
可是我家很小，還有小孩耶
My place is spacious, and there's no one else.
我家很大，而且沒人喔
I have medaka. Would you like to see them?
家裡還養了稻田魚 要不要來我家看看？
What's wrong with you? Read the room a little and scram!
你在搞什麼東西啊？ 起碼看看別人的臉色，老實滾蛋
I'm sorry.
抱歉啦
But telling a woman, "Don't worry, I won't do anything!" is inappropriate.
但對女性說“放心，我什麼都不幹” 就等同出局耶
Why?
哪裡出局了？
Accidents like that are just what happens between men and women!
男女相處不就是嘴上說不幹 卻會情不自禁更進一步嗎？
The next morning, she'd say, "You said you wouldn't do anything."
隔天一早，女方會說 “你說過什麼都不幹的”
And you grin at each other while having coffee.
一大早喝著咖啡，對彼此相視一笑
That'd be an act of indecency without consent.
那屬於不合意猥褻罪
Any sexual activity without consent is a crime.
未經同意的所有性行為皆是犯罪
What? Isn't it consent when she lets you into her place?
什麼？對方讓我進屋的當下 就等於合意吧？
To avoid misunderstandings like that,
為了避免發生那種誤解
our company recommends the sexual consent app.
我們公司推薦使用性同意應用程式
You give consent by scanning this QR code.
掃描QR碼代表雙方同意
So it has to go like this?
所以重點是什麼？
"I won't do anything, so let me come over."
“我什麼都不幹，讓我留宿”
"But I want something to happen." "Are you sure?"
“別這麼說，你就幹吧” “你確定？”
"Of course!"
“請便！”
Or you can't have rumpy-pumpy?
除非女方這麼說 否則不能做那檔子事？
You don't.
通常不會做啦
You don't?
不會做？
Don't you want to have rumpy-pumpy? At your age?
你都這年紀了卻不想做那檔子事？
What's the joy in life, then?
你活到現在有什麼樂趣可言啊？
Dating isn't a good bang for your buck.
談戀愛性價比太低了
Huh? What's that?
什麼？“性價比”是什麼玩意兒？
Wait, don't tell me.
慢著，你先別說
I'll Google it.
我Google一下
This is my mom. She died five years ago from an illness.
這是我媽媽
I see.
這樣啊
She was hospitalized for a long time.
她住院很長一段時間
I was mentally prepared for it.
我當時已經做好心理準備了
But my dad became so depressed, it was almost laughable.
但我老爸他啊
He would sit there every night and cry.
每晚都會坐在那裡哭
So right now, I'm behaving like a delinquent to distract him.
所以我現在
This is before we got married.
這張是我們婚前拍的
Yuri was so young here.
那時的百合好年輕啊
Isn't she cute? She's nine years younger than me.
可愛吧？她小我九歲
She was a student who came for teaching practice,
她當年是來教育實習的女大生
and I seduced her after assuring her I wouldn't do anything.
我就是用“什麼都不幹” 這招追到她的
This is her first letter to me.
這是她給我的第一封信
And this is my reply.
這是我給她的回信
MS. YURI SHIRAI
（白井百合小姐）
This is us in Kamakura, where we had our first date.
這是我們初次約會去鎌倉拍的照片
And here's the charm we bought there.
還有在當地買的護身符
This is us at Expo'70.
這張是在大阪萬博拍的
And our ticket.
還有票根呢
This is Junko's first visit to a shrine.
這張是純子第一次到神社參拜時拍的
This is Junko's umbilical cord.
這是純子的臍帶
This is her baby teeth.
還有她的乳牙
So you keep all your keepsakes in that bag.
你的所有回憶都裝在那個袋子裡啊
Yeah, I carry it with me.
是啊，我隨身帶著走
Oh, do you want to watch a video?
對了，要不要看錄影帶？
It's of Junko dancing to Pink Lady. Where's your VCR?
有拍下純子跳粉紅淑女歌曲的樣子 放映機在哪裡？
I don't have one.
-我家沒有 -什麼？
Yet? It's more like…
不是還沒買啦…
I can watch whatever I want at any time with my subs.
現在就算沒有放映機 也能用訂閱服務隨時看影片
Su… sub…
訂…
Whatever.
隨便啦
You keep saying things I don't understand. I can't keep up at all.
淨說些我聽不懂的話 我根本就跟不上
I want to return to the Showa era and watch Tonight.
好想回到昭和看“TONIGHT”喔
So it's just been you and your daughter for a while now?
你一直都跟女兒同住？
That's the promise I made to my wife.
我答應過妻子
I'll make sure she doesn't get involved with bad guys
會在女兒高中畢業前好好守著她
until she finishes high school.
好讓她不被壞傢伙纏上
She's a bit wanton, but she's not stupid.
她雖然輕佻，但並不笨
My mom asked me to stay with him until I graduate from high school.
媽媽拜託我在高中畢業前 陪在老爸身邊
And without me, my dad would be weeping all alone anyway.
要是沒有我陪著 老爸會獨自一人哭哭啼啼的
You never know,
誰知道呢
maybe he's contemplating remarriage.
也許他正想著再婚呢
My dad?
你說老爸嗎？
No way. That's impossible.
不可能
Not when he's still watching videos like this at the age of 50.
都過了50歲還在看這種錄影帶 想再婚根本沒門
That farting geezer.
他就只是個愛放屁的老頭
He never stops, you know.
他一放就放不停
He wakes up with a fart and comes walking here farting,
起床時總是伴著放屁聲 再靠著放屁的推力一路走到這
like "Pfft, pfft, pfft."
就像這樣“噗…”
That geezer is late today.
那老頭今天真晚回來
Junko.
純子
Listen.
聽我說句話
Kiyoshi, come here.
阿清，你也過來
What's with this serious mood?
幹嘛這麼嚴肅？
Did he die? Is he dead?
他死了嗎？難道老爸翹辮子了？
Junko.
純子
Listen to me calmly.
冷靜點聽我說
No way. How did he die? Was it heart failure?
天哪，不會吧？死因是什麼？
Will I inherit? I'll get everything, right?
拿得到遺產嗎？ 我能拿到所有遺產吧？
He's alive.
他還活著
But he's not in this world.
不過他不在這個世界
So he's dead, then!
那不就是死了嗎？
-He's not. -What?
-他沒有死 -怎麼回事？
He's alive and well in another world.
他在另一個世界過得好好的
So he's unable to pass on. Is he a lingering ghost?
你的意思是他沒辦法好好成佛囉？
Is that why you look so serious?
所以你才會擺出一張嚴肅臉？
I was born with this look.
我天生就是嚴肅臉
Aiko Gibo?
宜保愛子？
Are you Aiko Gibo?
大嬸是宜保愛子嗎？
I'm not Aiko Gibo!
我並不是宜保愛子！
I never imagined there would come a day when I'd yell, "I'm not Aiko Gibo!"
沒想到有一天我還得大聲澄清 “我並不是宜保愛子！”
Put simply, your father is now in the future.
簡單來說
Do you understand? He traveled through time.
聽得懂嗎？
We came from the future.
我們是從未來來的
We came from 2024, so that's 38 years from now.
我們來自2024年，距今38年後
Professor Masakazu Inoue of the Metropolis Institute of Technology
首都工業大學的井上昌和教授 帶領研究團隊
and his research team collaborated with NASA to invent the time machine.
與美國太空總署合作 研發出一號時光機
He renovated a Showa-era route bus.
他改造了一輛昭和的公車
This guy. He's my dad.
就是他，他是我爸爸
He's an inventor.
他是研發者
Several trial runs were privately conducted,
有幾次的行駛實驗都是暗地進行
and as his family members, we were given priority access.
我們這些家屬也得以優先試乘
Everyone returned safely,
而大家都平安返回
but Kiyoshi said he didn't want to go back.
阿清卻說他不想回去
In exchange, there was some sort of mix-up,
小川老師則和我們立場對調 因為出了差錯
and Mr. Ogawa ended up traveling to 2024 and is unable to return.
到了2024年後便回不來
Do you understand?
你懂了嗎？
This thing…
這東西…
is a TV?
居然是電視？
It's so thin!
好薄一台！
True. It's strange, isn't it? But what's more strange is…
是啊，是挺神奇的
You can even turn the page. This is so cool!
還可以翻頁呢
You can even zoom in.
這麼做還能放大
Kiyoshi!
阿清！
Look at his nostrils!
鼻孔看得一清二楚！
You can even see his nose hair.
甚至看得清鼻毛
Anyway, until your father returns, we will live here with you.
總而言之
We're going to cohabit?
我們要同居？
Gosh, it's like something from Tonda Couple.
討厭啦，那就跟 《飛翔的情侶》一樣了嘛
You will have separate rooms.
你們不睡同一間房
Well then, shall we take a bath?
那麼，我們去洗澡吧
-Yeah. -Absolutely not.
-好 -別給我同意！
Thank you for shopping with us.
謝謝惠顧
I've got nothing to do.
好閒喔
Maybe I'll check out the school.
去學校看看好了
You little! What's going on between you and Junko Ogawa?
臭小子！你跟小川純子是什麼關係？
Junko is my chick.
純子
-So, yeah. -Say what?
-給我記好 -你說什麼？
We're cohabiting, so yeah.
我們正在同居
Don't act all cocky with us, you little wimp!
你這廢物小子少得意！
Crap. It's Mutchy's ghost bicycle.
不妙，是阿睦學長的幽靈自行車
Mutchy, that's me!
阿睦登場！
Let's scram!
我們走！
Why did you help me?
你為何願意救我？
After a one-on-one fight, you become buddies.
既然曾經一對一決鬥過 我們就是死黨了
A line from Let's Dachiko.
此話出自
Mutchy, thanks for being cozy with me.
學長
The way you use that word is weird, so study this.
你用這詞的方式有點噁心 多學著點吧
And the school uniform is formal wear for a delinquent,
還有啊，立領制服是不良少年的正裝
so look sharp in it.
給我穿得有型點
All right, come with me. I'll give you my shortened uniform.
懂了嗎？跟我來
Right.
好的
NITORI
（宜得利）
"Ni… to… ri"?
“宜得利”
To think it'd be turned into Nitori.
這裡竟然變成宜得利了
What now?
怎麼辦？
I can't stay in this world forever.
我要永遠待在這邊的世界嗎？
If I board a bus going the other way,
如果搭乘反向的公車
I might be able to travel back to the past.
說不定就能回到過去
I'm concerned about Junko.
我好擔心純子
But I'm even more concerned about Nagisa.
但我更不放心就這樣留下小渚
Junko or Nagisa?
該選純子還是小渚？
This is so frustrating. If only there were two of me.
好煩惱喔
Oh, there are!
啊，確實有！
Sorry.
抱歉
Ichiro Ogawa in 1986 is 50.
1986年的小川市郎已經50歲了
Ichiro, 38 years later, will be 88!
38年後的市郎
An 88-year-old me should be in this world somewhere!
這裡有88歲的我
Is it possible? I'm not sure if I'll even live until 88.
有可能嗎？
My lungs are probably black, and my blood pressure is reaching 140.
我的肺多半已經全黑了
No, even if I were alive, what can an 88-year-old man do?
不，即便我還活著
Can he have rumpy-pumpy? Will he even want to?
還能做那檔子事嗎？
NAGISA MOBILE PHONE
（小渚 手機）
Hello?
喂？
Mr. Ogawa, where are you right now?
喂？小川先生
Uh, I think I'm in Shinagawa. But it's not the Shinagawa I know.
這個嘛，應該是在品川
What do you see?
你看得到什麼？
Can you use the map app on your smartphone?
你會用智慧型手機上的 地圖應用程式嗎？
Map? Let's see.
地圖？我看看地圖
Can you come over to EBS TV Station right now?
你現在能來趟EBS電視台嗎？
When I arrived to collect my belongings, things got a bit messy.
我來拿私人物品 結果事情變得有點棘手
What? Did something happen?
怎麼了？出了什麼事？
Sorry. Never mind.
抱歉，不用了
Don't be like that. You called, so tell me.
搞什麼？
I don't think there's anything you can do for me right now.
我覺得現在沒什麼是你能做的
That's not true!
才沒那回事！
What you want me to do now is what I can do for you!
你現在希望我做的，我一定能做到！
"Ma… ru… e… tsu"?
“maruetsu”？
I see a store with Maruetsu written in Romaji.
我看到一間羅馬拼音為 “maruetsu”的店家
Baby wipes.
嬰兒濕紙巾
Please buy me baby wipes.
請你幫我買嬰兒濕紙巾
Please let me pass.
請你讓開
If you leave now, it's going to be tough for us.
如果你現在離開會為難公司
What about the new assistants?
請問一下 那個新來的助理製作人呢？
They both quit.
兩個都辭職了
They said they didn't join the company to do tedious jobs
她們說自己來這工作
like making copies and distributing bento boxes.
不是為了做複印文件 或分發午餐這類的雜務
Maybe you're the one who could use some counseling.
我想需要諮商的人是瓜生先生你
Even the counselor is on leave.
連諮商師也休職了
He has had a mental breakdown.
他心理出問題了
-I see. -Anyway…
-我知道了 -總而言之…
We can talk it out. So please reconsider.
我會創造對談的環境
Reconsider!
你重新考慮啦！
-Reconsider! -Please let go of me!
-我求你再想想！ -就說了請你住手！
Talking won't help.
對話也沒用
Ryusuke? How?
龍介？
I sent you my schedule, didn't I?
我把行程表傳給你了吧？
I have a quiz show to film on Monday.
星期一要來錄一檔問答節目
Restraining her would infringe upon Article 22 of the Constitution,
瓜生先生，若你繼續攔住她 將違反憲法第22條的
which guarantees the freedom to choose one's occupation.
職業選擇自由
I'm aware of that.
我當然知道
Ryusuke…
龍介…
I know your personality well. So, I won't stop you from leaving.
我深知你的性子
I will accept everything.
我會接受這一切
Do you mean you'll divorce me?
你這話指的是
On one condition. I will have custody of our child.
只不過呢
Because you're not suited for parenting.
理由是你不適合養育孩子
Nowadays, childcare isn't restricted to women.
這個時代不再侷限於 一定要由女性養孩子
I've been considering shifting my focus to online streaming
我剛好在考慮將重心轉往串流媒體
and moving my operations overseas.
並將活動據點遷移至海外
I'm relocating to Sweden, a country with excellent childcare benefits.
我打算移民到瑞典 那裡擁有相當先進的育兒福利
This would be better for Masato's future as well.
為正人的將來著想，就該那麼做
No.
我拒絕
I will raise Masato.
我會撫養正人
Don't try to carry everything on your own.
不要什麼事都想一肩扛下
Is it wrong to shoulder everything alone?
凡事自己扛不行嗎？
BABY WIPES
（嬰兒濕紙巾）
The whole nation is working toward promoting the Work Style Reform now.
日本正以舉國之力 針對工作風格推動改革
What the hell is a "work style" anyway?
“工作風格”是什麼鬼東西？
Do you know him?
你認識他？
What other work styles exist besides working like crazy or like a horse?
工作方式除了“賣力”和“投入” 還有什麼？
How old are you?
你今年幾歲？
I was born in Showa 10.
我生於昭和10年
So I'm 88.
今年88歲了
Eighty-eight!
米壽之年！
You look young for your age.
你看起來好年輕喔
I'm a product Of the Japanese Economic Miracle
我是身處高度成長期的天賜之子
I work from morning till night
日夜不輟辛勤工作
I work even in my dreams
連在夢中也依舊不停幹活
I felt like I had become an old man
覺得自己成了老頭子
The night I turned 88
米壽之夜
We implement shift work to prevent an overload on specific employees
為了不讓部分員工承受過多負擔 安排輪班制度
and prevent unpaid overtime and overwork.
防止無酬加班和過勞
That's the Work Style Reform.
這正是所謂的工作方式改革
This reform isn't helping her at least.
那項改革沒幫上她吧
It's simpler for her to manage things alone,
她覺得這樣還不如一個人扛
which is why she's doing things on her own.
才會迫不得已獨自承擔
That's her work style
那就是她的工作方式
If she works overtime, her juniors would have to do the same.
要是她一個人加班 後進也無法按時下班啊
No, they should just leave, saying, "I'm done for the day!"
回去就好啦
That's their work style
這就是那些人的工作方式
There's this thing called peer pressure.
你不知道世上有所謂的同儕壓力嗎？
An atmosphere that makes it hard to say no
難以拒絕的氣氛
That's peer pressure
同儕壓力
An atmosphere that makes it hard to leave
難以下班的氣氛
An atmosphere That makes it hard to request time off
難以請假的氣氛
That's peer pressure
同儕壓力
They say it's not mandatory
嘴上說不強制
But the air they exude Makes it hard to refuse
卻瀰漫著不能違逆的氣氛
Let's call it a day, leave work on the dot
今天就到此為止，準時下班吧
Let's quietly take work home
默默將工作帶回家做
Instead of pushing yourself Until you break down
若要勉強自己到累倒的程度
It's better to leave work on schedule
還不如按時下班
And lie down
回家躺平
Revolting.
真讓人倒胃口
Revolting?
倒胃口？
Is it mandatory to leave work on schedule?
按時下班是強制規定嗎？
What a joke.
別開玩笑了
Let me choose my own work style, at least!
至少該讓人自己決定工作方式吧！
Your ideas are too extreme. They don't align with the current times!
你的觀點太過極端 跟不上現代社會的價值觀
Do I have to conform to the times?
人必須得跟上時代嗎？
You people talk about the Showa era as if it were all bad,
嘴上老說昭和怎樣 講得昭和好像很邪惡似的
but at least the economy was stronger back then compared to now.
昭和再不濟，景氣也比現在好
I can't argue with that.
說到這一點我就無法反駁了
But either way, she's going to quit.
算了，反正她一定會辭職
I won't quit.
我不會辭職
-Really? -Yes.
-真的嗎？ -真的
I kind of felt upset,
因為他搞得我很火大
so I decided to quit quitting.
我決定不辭職了
In exchange, Mr. Uryu,
作為交換，瓜生先生
would you allow me to have things my way?
你是否能答應我的一些任性要求？
Even though having you accommodate me makes me feel a little bad.
雖然你處處為我著想
Let me make four requests
請答應我的四個任性要求
Please consider them
希望你能考慮一下
Was that Naomi Chiaki?
千秋直美？
First, I'll do things on my own
第一個要求，讓我自己做事
A raise
就是加薪
Third, move the daycare room
第三個要求，托兒室的位置
From the annex to the main building
設在本棟，而不是分棟
Fourth, don't rush
第四個要求，推動無紙化可以
Going paperless
但不要這麼急嘛
I hear you, but young people nowadays grow up using tablets.
我知道，可是最近的年輕人 都是看平板長大的
And upper management promotes paperless--
高層也說要推動無紙化
But they're out of touch with the situation.
但高層自己就無法適應啊
They still request scripts in paper form and want visual materials on DVDs,
不是要求紙本腳本 就是要求將影像資料燒錄成光碟
which only adds to our workload.
每遇上這種情況 我們的工作量就會爆增
Fifth, make sure our lunch break is
第五個要求，午餐時間
At least one hour long
最少保障一小時
Didn't she say four?
剛才只說有四個要求吧？
Sixth, implement shifts
第六個要求，學會工作內容後
After new employees have learned Their responsibilities
再開始輪班制
Seventh, end the practice Of TV personalities
第七個要求，針對演藝人員
Greeting their fellow cast members In the dressing room
採用不須至休息室問候的方針
Eighth, don't take away
第八個要求，拜託不要削減
My motivation
我的工作熱情
Nagisa…
小渚…
Even if it means working a bit overtime,
就算得加一點班
take the time to review your subordinate's project plans.
請空出一些時間看下屬的企劃書吧
Without such flexibility, discretion, or leeway,
如果這點都無法通融 不體恤對方，沒有讓步的空間
you can't create anything interesting.
必定催生不了有趣的事物
If you make exceptions like that, it will result in death from overwork.
一旦認可那種特例 遲早會出現過勞死案例
Is the point of the Work Style Reform to diminish your employees' motivation?
削減員工士氣 就是改革工作方式的目的？
Listen. I said you could return to the office,
聽好了，我同意你重返職場
but I didn't tell you to make something interesting.
但沒逼你創造出有趣的作品
You…
你這個人…
…are right, but have no heart.
只會說正確的大道理，但不懂得人心
I handed you divorce papers,
我都寄離婚協議書給你了
and all you can come up with is sound arguments?
這時候你還要講大道理？
Are you an AI? Are you HusbandGPT?
你是人工智慧嗎？ 還是老公型聊天機器人？
If you can't talk calmly, let's talk another time.
若你無法冷靜談話，還是下次再聊吧
I'm not suited for parenting.
我不適合養育孩子？
You think I don't know that?
那種事我也知道！
Even so, I have to do it and I want to do it.
不適合卻非做不可，我自己也有意願
If you think I'm not cut out for it,
既然你覺得我不夠格
do what you want me to do, not what you can do.
那就由你來吧，別做些你能做到的 而是做我希望你能做的
Stop this.
別再這樣了
I'm not sure what type of harassment this is,
我不知道這樣是構成什麼騷擾罪
but it's my primary source of stress.
但你這樣指的動作 是我最大的壓力來源
He passed gas.
他放屁了
He hasn't passed gas at all today.
他今天本來沒放過屁，一次都沒有
You farted, Machato!
你放屁了呢，正人！
Thank goodness.
太好了
Sorry, that was me.
不好意思啊，剛剛放屁的人是我
Give me a break.
真受不了你
Goodness.
你說是不是？
-Huh?
-什麼？
He farted!
他放屁了！
Masato's custody was given to Nagisa by mutual agreement.
後來雙方同意正人的 監護權歸小渚所有
Funny, huh?
你瞧，很有趣吧？
I was also faced with an unexpected opportunity.
而我也迎來了意想不到的轉機
Mr. Ogawa, this is our personnel manager.
小川先生，這位是我們的人事部長
Let me cut to the chase,
恕我直言，小川先生
could you work as our company's counselor?
你能不能來本公司做諮商師？
What? Me?
什麼？你說我嗎？
You can't hire someone like me.
我這種人當不了啦
Your extreme logic made a fool of someone wielding sound arguments,
你以極端的觀點 說贏滿嘴大道理的對手
while also providing others with food for thought.
還創造機會讓旁人思考 你的思維邏輯
It was truly impressive.
實在是無比傑出
I only said what I wanted to.
我只是說出自己的心聲罷了
People today are constrained by common sense.
現代人容易被常識所困
What we need is extreme arguments rather than sound ones.
本公司需要的不是正確的觀點 而是極端觀點
-Someone individualistic like you-- -Okay. I'll do it.
-像你這種性格鮮明… -可以，我答應
-Are you sure? -Not for very long, though.
-真的嗎？ -但我不會做太久
Or my daughter will have rumpy-pumpy.
不然我女兒會做那檔子事
Kiyoshi!
阿清！
-What happened to you? -Huh?
-你這是怎樣？ -怎麼了？
I got Mutchy to make a man out of me.
阿睦學長讓我變成了男子漢
Please no.
討厭啦
It's the type of appearance I find least attractive.
這種外型我最厭惡了
Pretty cool.
好酷喔
Thanks.
謝囉
Well, you can't compete with Ghibli.
如果同時段在播吉卜力就束手無策了
-Right. Thank you. -Let's go.
好的，非常感謝你
-Speak louder! -Excuse me.
-大聲說出來！ -好的，告辭了
All these people are mentally weak.
每個人都那副德行 正確心態都沒練出來
Well then…
那麼…
JUNKO 1978 PINK LADY
（純子，1978 粉紅淑女）
Okay, go!
好了，請開始！
Good morning.
早安
Morning.
早啊
I saw the videos of the overseas location. They looked amazing.
我看了你到國外拍的外景，超棒的
Oh, yeah?
真的假的？
I got to fly business class, so I made an extra effort.
你讓我搭飛機時坐商務艙 所以我簡直是拚了命在拍
Thank you so much.
謝謝你
I'm the one who should thank you.
哪裡，彼此彼此
Are you sure I'm the right fit?
不過我這樣真的可以嗎？
I'll keep saying inappropriate things.
我日後還是會經常失言
Your disregard for compliance makes your words hit home.
正因為你不合乎現代規範 講出來的話才能直戳人心
Especially for us modern-day people who are immersed in compliance culture.
畢竟我們這些現代人 做事早已習慣照著規矩來
COMPLIANCE
（現代規範）
You're fast!
你打字速度好快喔！
But I have presbyopia, so I can't read.
但我有老花眼，看不清楚
If you do this, the text will get bigger.
這麼一滑就放大囉
What?!
你說什麼？
I still have so much to learn.
看來我不知道的東西還多著呢
Teach me more, Nagisa.
多教我一點，小渚
Can I come over tonight? I won't do anything.
我今晚可以去你家嗎？我什麼都不幹
Stop. That's sexual harassment.
不可以，再說下去就是性騷擾了
I don't mind if you do.
我不介意啊
I was just joking.
討厭，我是開玩笑的
Of course, you were!
我想也是！
Don't go, Akitsu! Don't read the room!
不要走，秋津！別這麼會看氣氛啊！
You'll make things awkward.
否則不就感覺別有深意嗎？
He left so quickly.
你說對不對？他馬上就閃人了
Earlier, why did I call you again?
我在那時候
Why? You wanted me to get baby wipes, didn't you?
你問原因嗎？
You said,
你那時對我說
"What you want me to do is what I can do for you."
“你現在希望我做的 我一定能做到”
It made me happy.
我聽了好開心
Even though my husband and the ward office abandoned me,
即便被丈夫和區公所捨棄
it made me think I still had you.
還有小川先生陪在我身邊
It encouraged me to keep going.
所以我才能加把勁努力
I, um…
所以我…
Thank you.
很感謝你
Well…
不用客氣
Where's Masato today?
正人今天去哪了？
My father is looking after him, so it's okay.
有我爸幫忙照顧他，不用擔心
Rumpy-pumpy is on, isn't it?
竟然有機會做那檔子事？
I'm in a pickle. What should I do?
這下傷腦筋了
Am I already going to meet her father?
頭一次登門就要見人家爸爸？
Anyway, I should refrain from drinking any more.
總之先不喝酒
Wait, am I going to do the deed?
話說真的要做那種事？
Since when? Since what? Is it okay?
我多久沒做了？睽違幾年了？
Why not? Even I want to enjoy some romance sometimes.
有何不可？
MOM
（媽媽）
What am I calling her for? What will I say?
打電話做什麼？
Am I going to ask Junko if I can have rumpy-pumpy?
難道要問純子說 “爸爸可以做那檔子事嗎？”
No signal?
沒有訊號？
Huh? Where's Mr. Ogawa?
奇怪，小川先生人呢？
He said he was going to get some fresh air.
他說要去外面吹吹風
Ow!
好痛！
No way.
不會吧…
Are you okay? Are you drunk, Mr. Ogawa?
怎麼了嗎？
Huh? What?
什麼？怎麼了？
What year is it?
現在是哪一年？
Showa 61.
昭和61年
What?!
字幕翻譯：劉維容
Time to make my rounds!
回診時間到了！
It's the most extreme show right now.
是目前最激進的節目
-What are you doing here? -Huh?
-你怎麼會在這裡？ -什麼？
Please don't. It will get taken out of context.
停下，不然之後會被剪下來
An inappropriate remark was made.
方才出現一些極度不妥的發言
Cut the crap already!
-給我適可而止！ -你才是呢！
You've fallen in love, haven't you?
你有喜歡的對象吧？
I promise I'll return.
我一定會回來